Guide to the James A. Healy Collection of Irish literature, 1870-1976
Department of Special Collections
- CATALOGUE OF MANUSCRIPT, BOXES 1-16
  - HEALY, JAMES A. TO GEORGE YEATS AND EILEEN COLUM (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 4-13-46., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 7-27-46., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 7-27-46., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 8-1-46., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 8-2-46., TLc - 4
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 11-25-46., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 9-4-47., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 5-28-48., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 8-31-48., TLS w/a [not sent?] - 3 (1), enc. list of books, TD - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 8-31-48., TLS [not sent?] - 1 (1)
    - JAH (NYC) to GY, 9-29-48., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to [GY], 2-1-50.Memo of books, [UNK] - 2
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 12-12-50., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 12-13-50., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 11-10-51(first letter)., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 11-10-51(second letter)., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 12-3-51., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 3-5-52., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 3-10-53., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 4-26-53., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 5-25-53., TLc - 1 enc. list of prints, TLc - 2
    - JAH (NP) to GY, 7-15-53., TLc - 1
  - HEALY, JAMES A. TO JACK B. YEATS (AND OTHERS CONCERNING LATTER'S PAINTINGS) (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 5-26-38., TLc w/a - 2
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 8-2-38., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 6-21-39., Trans. of telegram: TL - 1
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 6-22-39., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 6-28-39., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 6-30-39., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 7-1-39., Trans. of telegram: TL - 1 (1)
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 7-11-39., Trans. of telegram: TL - 1 (1)
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 7-18-39., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NYC) to Jack BY, 1-26-40., TLc w/a - 5
    - JAH (NYC) to Jack BY, 5-29-40., TLc w/a - 5
    - JAH (NYC) to Jack BY, 6-11-40., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 11-26-45., TLc w/a - 4
    - JAH (NYC) to Jack BY, 11-27-45., TLc w/a - 3
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 8-17-46., TLc - 4, enc. 2 checks
    - JAH (NYC) to Jack BY, 11-25-46., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 5-28-48., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NP) to Jack BY, 5-29-52., TLc - 7
    - JAH (NYC) to Jack BY, 7-13-53., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to Jack BY, 7-4-55., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NP) to John Farrell, 6-5-39., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NP) to Patric Farrell, 6-16-39., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NCY) to Patric Farrell, 7-18-39., TLc - 2
    - JAH (NYC) to Patric Farrell, 3-9-40., TLc - 3
    - JAH (NYC) to Patric Farrell, 3-25-40., TLc - 1
    - List of paintings, ND., TD - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to Willard Gallery, 4-11-62., TLc - 1
  - HEALY, JAMES A. TO LILY YEATS (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - JAH (NYC) to LY, 5-25-38., TLc - 2 w/ memo of check
    - JAH (NYC) to LY, 8-15-38., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to LY, 10-5-38., TLc - 3 w/ 2 mailing receipts
    - JAH (NYC) to LY, 11-23-38., TLc - 2
  - HEALY, JAMES A. TO WILLIAM BUTLER YEATS (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - JAH (NP) to WBY, 10-1-37., TLc - 4
    - JAH (NP) to WBY, 6-22-38., TLc - 4
    - JAH (NP) to WBY, 8-9-38., TLc - 1
    - JAH (NYC) to WBY, 8-14-38., TLc - 1
  - HEALY, JAMES A. TO OTHER RECIPIENTS, A-I (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - HEALY, JAMES A. TO OTHER RECIPIENTS, H-Z (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - HENRY, PAUL (Box 8, Folder 115)
    - PH (Kilmanocogue) to RC, 5-20-30., ALS - 4
    - PH (Bray) to RC, 5-20/30-31., Telegrams - 5
    - PH (Bray) to RC, 8-16-31., ALS - 2
    - PH (D) to RC, ND., ALS - 2
    - PH (K) to RC, 5-24-34., ALS - 4
    - PH (K) to RC, 12-12-34., ALS - 3
    - PH (K) to JAH 8-6-31., ALS - 2
    - PH (K) to JAH 1-1-34., ALS - 4
    - PH (Belfast) to JAH, 4-4-34., Telegram - 1
    - PH (K) to JAH, 5-24-34., ALS - 6
    - PH (K) to JAH, 12-13-34., ALS - 3
    - PH (K) to JAH, 10-31-35., ALS - 1
    - PH (K) to JAH, 9-12-36., ALS - 4
    - PH (K) to JAH, 10-6-36., Telegram - 1
    - PH (K) to JAH, 10-7-36., ALS - 2
    - PH (K) to JAH, 11-27-36., Telegram - 1
    - PH (K) to JAH, 11-28-36., ALS - 3
    - PH (K) to JAH, 7-17-37., ALS - 1
    - PH (K) to JAH, 12-25-38., Telegram - 1
    - PH (K) to JAH, 10-10-51., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - PH (K) to JAH, 11-19-51., TLS - 3 w/cov.
    - PH (Bray) to JAH, 2-10-53., TLS - 2 and postscript - 1, w/cov.
    - PH (K) to JAH, 9-12-55., TLS - 2 w/cov.
    - Ca. 30 clippings re PH
    - Typed copy of article on, NP, ND., TDc - 1
    - Photo of, beside painting -, (8)
    - 5 reproductions of paintings on Christmas cards to JAH -, 4 of them signed
    - Printed invitation card to exhibition, 1934, 1
    - Catalogues of paintings at Combridge's, London -, 3 (2)
    - Catalogue of paintings at Mrs. Sullivan's, NYC -, 1 (2)
    - Reproduction of painting on cover of Literary Digest, 1931, 1, and article re - 1
    - Copies of reviews, 1929-30., TD - 3
    - Copy of Art Digest review of Irish exhibit, 4-1-[?], TD - 2
  - HEARST, MILLICENT (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - Hearst, Millicent ([NYC]) to RC, 5-11-31., ALS - 3
    - Hearst, Millicent (NYC) to RC, 4-14-32., Telegram - 1
    - Hearst, Millicent (NYC) to RC, 5-3-32., Telegram - 1
  - HIGGINS, F. R. (Box 8, Folder 117)
    - Higgins, F. R. (Rathfarnham) to OG, ND., ALS - 1 (3) and trans.: TL - 1
    - Higgins, F. R. (Ballina, Co. Mayo) to AE, 1-18-30., ALS - 1
    - Higgins, F. R. (Ballina, Co. Mayo) to AE, 1-22-30., ALS - 1
  - HINKSON, PAMELA; HOEING, CHARLES (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - [Hinkson?], Pamela (NP) to AE, Sunday., ANS - 1
      3 clippings about
    - Hinkson, Pamela (D) to The Irish Times, 1-25-65., Xerox of printed clipping - 1
    - Hinkson, Pamela, list of Parnell papers owned by., TD - 2
    - Hoeing, Charles (Rochester, N. Y.) to AE, 2-5-27., ALS - 2
  - HOOVER, HERBERT; HOULT, NORAH (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - Hoover, Herbert (Washington, D.C.) to RC, 1-21-32., Printed invitation card - 1, w/ carte d'entree - 1, w/cov.
    - Hoover, Herbert (NYC) to OG, 10-20-44., Pc of TLS - 1 (2)
    - Hoult, Norah (NYC) to JAH, 12-7-38., TLS - 1 w/cov.
  - HYDE, DOUGLAS (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - [Hyde, Douglas] (Roscommon) to Martin E. Bruin, [5?]-8-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Hyde, Douglas (Roscommon) to JAH, [7]-11]38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Hyde, Douglas (NP) to [ECY], ND., Printed acknowledgement of election congratulations - 2, w/a by ECY on back - 1
    - Hyde, Douglas (Roscommon) to ECY, 9-8-33., ALS - 2
    - Hyde, Douglas (Roscommon) to ECY, 9-16-33., ALS - 2
    - [Hyde, Douglas] (Earlsport Place, [D?]) to [?JBY], 11-23-?, ALS - 4, w/cov. annotated by ECY
    - Hyde, Douglas (County Roscommon), cover dated 1904?to John Quinn., AD - 1
    - Exhibit on, 1949,at Library of Congress: list, TDc - 5, w/ exchange of letters between JAH and Librarian - 2
    - List for auction of Hyde's library, [1949]., TmimeoD - 3
    - List for auction of Hyde's library, [1949]., TmimeoD - ca. 30
    - Ca. 10 clippings re, 1938
  - I (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - IRISH ACADEMY OF LETTERS (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - List of members, (NP), ND., TDc - 1 (2)
    - Rules of Academy (D), 1932., Printed pamphlet
    - Robinson, Lennox (D) to OG, 10-6-49., TLS - 1
    - OG (NP) to [Eugene Kinkead], [ca. 9-15-50]., AN - 1, enc. Lennox Robinson to OG, 8-23-50, TLS - 1; and Lennox Robinson to Acdemician, (D), July 1950, TmimeoL - 1 w/a by OG
    - OG (NP) to JAH, [2]28-51]., AN - 1, enc. list of nominees, TDc - 1 w/cov.
    - Irish Academy and AE, ca. 10 clippings, 1932-52
    - Clipping re Mary Lavin -, 2
    - Cliping re W.R. Rodgers -, 2
  - J (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - JOHNSTON, CHARLES (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Johnston, Charles (N.J.) to EAB, 6-12-15., TL S - 4 (1)
    - Johnston, Charles (N.J.) to EAB, 7-8-15., TLS - 1 (1)
  - JOYCE, JAMES (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - Joyce, James (Zurich) to EAB, 3-15-17., ALS - 1 (1) and trans.
    - Joyce, James (Zurich) to EAB, 4-13-17., ALS - 1 (1) and trans.
    - Joyce, James (Paris) to EAB, 7-30-20., ALS - 1 (1) and trans.
    - Joyce, James (Kensington) to PC, 7-2-31., ALS - 2 (1) and trans.
    - [Joyce, James] Stephen Dedalus (D) to OG, 6-3-04., Trans: TL - 1
    - Joyce, James, Gas from a Burner (Flushing), Sept. 1912., Printed broadside - 1
    - Ellmann, Joyce in Love, 1959., Printed monograph
    - Sale description re The Day of Rabblement (1901)., TD - 1
    - Clipping, 2-5-49, James Joyce in Zurich, Irish Times -, 1
    - OG, article, James Augustine Joyce, 1949., Booklet
    - OG, article, They Think They Know Joyce, Saturday Review, 3-18-50
    - Ellmann, Richard, article, Odyssey of a Unique Book, N.Y. Times Magazine, 11-14-65
    - Kerrigan, Anthony, article, Joyce's Grave, Irish Times clipping, 12-11-65
  - K (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - KEATING, JOHN (Box 9, Folder 127)
    - Gallery exhibit leaflet, 1930, (2)
    - Ca. 12 clippings, some with photos of Keating and reproductions of his paintings, 1939-61
  - KING, FREDERICK A. (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - King, F.A. (NYC) to JAH, [8-8-39]., TLS - 1
    - King, F.A. (NYC) to JAH, ND., TLS - 2
    - Clipping re death of, 11-1-39, (2)
    - [King, F.A.?], article, The Decline of the Irish Drama [end missing[in The Nineteenth Century, April 1925, pp. 578-586
    - JAH, notes of purchases from King, AD/TD - 2
  - KINKEAD, E.F. (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - EFK [NYC] to JAH, 12-1-38., ANS - 1 w/cov.
    - EFK (NYC) to JAH, 6-22-39., TLS - 2
    - EFK (NP) to JAH, 1-29-40., Draft TL - 1 (2)
    - EFK (NP) to OG, 2-26-42., TLS - 1
    - EFK (NYC), draft for speech [?]re Joe McGarrity., ADS - 4
    - EFK (NP) to Henry Shepard, ND., Draft of letter recommending OG as a doctor, TLc - 1
    - EFK (NP) to Henry Shepard, 3-25-44., TLc - 1
    - EFK (NP) to GY, 2-1-39., Telegram - TDc - 1
    - EFK (NYC) to GY, 2-2-39., TLc w/a - 1 w/cov addressed to JAH
    - EFK (NP) to GY, 3-31-39., TLc - 1
    - Clipping re, 3-27-51
  - L (Box 9, Folder 130)
  - LANE, SIR HUGH; LARKIN, JAMES; LE BRAZ, ANATOLE; LECKY, WALTER (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - Lane, Sir Hugh (D) to ECY, 5-17-[05?]., ALS - 3
    - [Larkin, James] (Chicago) to My dear Boy, 6-21-16., Trans: TL -1
    - Le Braz, Anatole (Rennes) to M. Bourgeois, 2-23-13., ALS -7 (1)
    - Le Braz, Anatole (Rennes) to M. Bourgeois, 3-6-13., APCS (1)
    - Lecky, Walter (L) to [Henry Reeve], 3-6-1886., ALS - 5
    - Lecky, Walter (L) to Henry Reeve, 2-28-1894., ALS - 2
    - Lecky, Walter (L) to Henry Reeve, 5-9-?., ALS - 2
  - LESLIE, SHANE (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - Leslie, Shane (Indiana) to RC, 2-25-35., ALS - 2
    - Leslie, Shane (L) to RC, 8-29-35., ALS - 2 (1)
    - Leslie, Shane (Washington) to RC, 3-11-39., ALS - 2
    - 2 clippings re, 1924, 1938
  - LONDON, CHARMIAN; LONGFORD, CHRISTINE (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - London, Charmian (Glen Ellen) to RC, 11-28-33., TLS - 2
    - London, Charmian (Glen Ellen) to Michael (?), 5-6-33., ALS - 8 and transcripts (2)
    - Longford, Christine (D) to Joseph Campbell, 12-30-33., TNS - 1
    - Clipping re -, 1
  - LYND, ROBERT; LYTELLTON, KATHARINE (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Lynd, Robert (L) to [Grant Richards], 7-24-07., ALS - 5
    - Lynd, Robert (Belfast) to Grant Richards, 7-31-07., AL [end missing] - 4
    - Lynd, Robert (L) to Grant Richards, 9-26-07., ALS - 4
    - 4 clippings re, 1951-55
    - Lytellton, Katharine (D) to LG, 4-5-[11?]., Trans: TL (2)
  - M (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - McCARTAN, PATRICK (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - McCartan, Patrick (Co. Wicklow) to JAH, 1-15-46., ALS - 3 w/cov. [He transcribes [ANSs] from GY to himself of 1-14-41 and 1-30-41.]
  - MACDONAGH, THOMAS (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - MacDonagh, Thomas (D) to M. Bourgeois, ?-22-[12]., ALS - 1
    - MacDonagh, Thomas (Rathfarnham) to M. Bourgeois, 5-30-11., TLS w/a - 2
    - MacDonagh, Thomas (Rathfarnham) to M. Bourgeois, 9-7-11., TLS - 2
  - McGONIGAL, MAURICE (Box 9, Folder 138)
    7 clippings re
  - MACGREEVY, THOMAS (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - MacGreevy, Thomas (D) to JAH, 2-23-64., ALS - 2 (1)
    - MacGreevy, Thomas (D) to JAH, 5-31-65., TLS - 1 w/cov.
    - Ca. 12 clippings re
  - MACLEOD, FIONA (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - Macleod, Fiona (Edinburgh) to Mr. LeGallienne, 3-16-1897., ALS - 2
    - Macleod, Fiona (L) to Grant Richards, 6-22-1899., ALS - 4
    - Macleod, Fiona (NP) to [Grant Richards], 7-10-1899., ALS - 3
    - Macleod, Fiona (NP) to [Grant Richards], 7-11-1899., ALS - 3
    - Macleod, Fiona (Midlothian) to [Mr. Stone], 1-31-[1895]., ALS - 10
    - Macleod, Fiona (L) to My dear Sir, 6-1-00., ALS - 2 (2)
    - Macleod, Fiona (Edinburgh) to My dear Sir, 11-31-01., ALS - 4 (2)
    - Macleod, Fiona (Midlothian) to My dear Sir, [1902]., TLS - 2 (2)
    - Auction notice re William Sharp and Fiona Macleod, 12-4-43
    - 3 clippings re Fiona Macleod controversy
  - MACMANUS, SEUMAS (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - MacManus, Seumas ([California]) to JAH, [12-8-39]., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - MacManus, Seumas (Donegal) to Mr. Holt, 7-6-1900., ALS - 2
    - Article by, The Irish Fairies, printed tearsheets - 6
    - Bibliography of, TD w/a - 1 (1)
    - Tearsheet from catalogue listing MacManus' books, ND - 2
    - 10 clippings re, 1938-53
  - MAGEE, W.K. (JOHN EGLINTON) AND MARIE (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 11-21-13., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 2-2-14., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 3-7-14., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 7-2-14., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 7-28-14., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 9-19-14., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 11-27-14., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 1-2-15., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 6-2-15., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 7-6-15., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 8-5-15., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 11-1-15., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 12-14-15., ALS - 2
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 1-26-16., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, ND [Feb.-May 1916?]., ALS - 2
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 5-29-16., ALS - 6
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 8-25-16., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 11-12-16., ALS - 3
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 11-25-20., ALS - 2
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 9-8-21., ALS - 3
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 10-13-21., ALS - 2
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 1-1-22., ALS - 3
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 2-20-22., ALS - 4
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 10-20-22., ALS - 2
    - WKM (D) to EAB, 12-23-22., ALS - 2
    - WKM (D) to [Dexter?], 4-9-13., ALS - 4
    - WKM (Bournemouth) to JAH, 1-13-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - WKM (Bournemouth) to JAH, 2-16-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - WKM (Bournemouth) to JAH, 5-10-38., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - WKM (Bournemouth) to JAH, 3-13-39., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - WKM (Bournemouth) to JAH, 2-4-55., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - [WKM] Eglinton, John, article, The Economics of Idealism from The New Age (8-14-13)., Pcs. of tearsheet - 1 (5)
    - Magee, Marie L. (Bournemouth) to JAH, 8-3-55., ALS - 1 w/cov.
  - MARKIEWICZ, CONSTANCE DE (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - C de M (NP) to [Gaelic term of address], ND., ALS - 2 and Battle Hymn, AD - 1 and trans.
    - C de M (NP) to [Gaelic term of address], 5-16-20., Pcs of ALS - 2, enc. ADS article, An Interlude - 6 (2)
    - Illustrated article on, in Eire Bulletin, 9-24-68
  - MARTYN, EDWARD (Box 9, Folder 144)
    - Martyn, Edward (D) to EAB, 5-19-14., ALS - 1
    - Martyn, Edward (D) to EAB, 7-2-14., ALS - 4
    - Martyn, Edward (Cork) to EAB, 7-24-14., ALS - 6 (2)
    - Martyn, Edward (Galway) to EAB, 8-25-15., ALS - 4
    - Martyn, Edward (Galway) to EAB, 10-5-15., ALS - 2
    - Martyn, Edward (D) to EAB, 10-23-18., ALS - 2 w/cov.
    - Martyn, Edward (Galway) to EAB, 7-27-18., ALS - 2
  - MASEFIELD, JOHN (Box 9, Folder 145)
    - Masefield, John (Oxford) to ECY, ND.(Will you...), ANS - 1
    - Masefield, John (Oxford) to ECY, ND., ANS - 1 (Many thanks)
    - Masefield, John (Oxford) to ECY, ND., ANS - 1 (Thank you...)
    - Masefield, John (Cirencester) to ECY, ND., TNS - 1
  - MAYNE, RUTHERFORD; MEYERSTEIN, E.H.W. (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - Mayne, R. (Samuel Waddell) (Ballinasloe) to EAB, 8-18-18., ALS - 2
    - Mayne, R. (Ballinasloe) to EAB, 9-17-18., ALS - 1
    - Clipping re, N.Y. Times, 1939 -, 1 (1)
    - Meyerstein, E.H. W. (L) to AE, 5-30-26., ALS - 2 (2) [written in verse]
  - MEGAW, ARTHUR S. (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Megaw, Arthur S. (Belfast) to AE, 7-24-31., Pc of ALS - 2 (3)
  - MERCIER, VIVIAN (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - Mercier, Vivian (NYC) to JAH, 6-25-57., ALS - 1
    - Mercier, Vivian (NYC) to JAH, 7-7-57., ALS - 4
    - Mercier, Vivian (NYC) to JAH, 11-7-57., ALS - 2
    - [Miller, Mary Owings. See Contemporary Poetry]
  - MILLIGAN, ALICE L.; MITCHELL, SUSAN L. (Box 10, Folder 149)
    - Milligan, Alice L. (Omagh, Co. Tyrone) to Editor [Joseph Campbell], [3-4-34]., ALS - 2, enc. AD poem, The Realm of Ulster by Eilis M.M. - 2 w/cov.
    - Milligan, Alice (Ballymagorry) to AE, 1-8-30., ALS - 3
    - Milligan, Alice, poem, When I Was a Little Girl, TD - 2
    - Milligan, Alice, obituary of, in Ireland bulletin, 4-20-53
    - Mitchell, Susan L. (D) to Dear Sir, 5-5-17., ALS - 1
    - Mitchell, Susan L. poem, Christmas, [6-25-23]., ADS - 1
    - [Mitchell, Susan L.], poem fragment, Calling us as it called us then..., AD - 1
  - MONAHAN, MICHAEL (Box 10, Folder 150)
    - MM (Conn.) to [RC], 7-1-23., ALS - 2
    - MM (Conn.) to RC, 1-3-29., ALS - 1
    - MM (Conn.) to RC, 7-26-29., ALS - 2
    - MM (Conn.) to RC, 12-28-31., ALS - 1
    - MM (Conn.) to RC, 1-11-32., ALS - 2
    - MM (Conn.) to RC, 12-8-32., ALS - 2
    - MM (Conn.) to RC, 3-7-33., ALS - 2
    - MM (NYC) to RC, 3-25-33., ALS - 2
    - MM (NP) to RC, 5-10-33., ALS - 2
    - MM (NP) to RC, 5-12-33., ALS - 3
    - MM (NYC) to RC, 6-9-33., ALS - 1
    - MM (NYC) to RC, [8-3-33]., APCS - 1
    - MM (NP) to RC, 8-29-33., TLS - 1
    - MM (NYC) to PC, 6-23-33., TRans. of TLc - 1
    - MM (NYC) to Charmain London, 6-23-33., Trans. of TLc - 1 (2)
    - MM (NYC) to George [Urquhardt], 5-3-33., Trans: TLc - 3
    - MM (Conn.) to Frederic [?], 12-6-22., Trans: TL - 1
    - Ca. 8 clippings etc.
  - MOORE, GEORGE (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - GM (L) to EAB, 7-2-14., TLS w/a - 4
    - GM (L) to EAB, 7-21-14., TLS w/a - 2
    - GM (L) to EAB, 7-23-14., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 8-17-14., TLS w/a - 5
    - GM (L) to EAB, 12-4-14., TLS - 2
    - GM (L) to EAB, 7-23-15., TLS w/a - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 8-27-15., TL - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 3-30-16., TLS - 1
    - GM (D) to EAB, 6-7?-[16]., ALS - 2 and trans.
    - GM (L) to EAB, 8-30-16., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 10-14-16., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 10-24-16., TLS - 4
    - GM (L) to EAB, 12-9-16., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 12-13-16., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 12-15-16., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 12-18-16., TLS w/a - 2
    - GM (L) to EAB, 1-10-17., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 3-22-17., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 8-16-17., TLS - 1
    - GM (L) to EAB, 8-29-17., TLS w/a - 2
    - GM (L) to EAB, 10-22-[17]., ALS - 2
    - GM (L) to EAB, 10-31-17., TLS - 2
    - GM (L) to Dear Sir, 7-21-14., TLS w/a - 2
    - Biographical note re GM, TDc - 1
    - 2 clippings, ND
  - MURPHY, SEAMUS (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - Murphy, Seamus (Cork) to Connie [?], 1-22-64., ALS - 2
    - 2 clippings re, 1954 and 1957
  - N (Box 10, Folder 153)
  - NEENAN, C.F., TO JAMES A. HEALY, 1949-62 (Box 10, Folder 154)
    Ca. 90 letters, not listed individually
  - O (Box 10, Folder 155)
  - O'BRIEN, FITZJAMES; O'BRIEN, FREDERICK; O'BRIEN, JAMES (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - O'Brien, Fitzjames (Camp McLellan, S.I.), requisition from quartermaster, 8-24-1861., PD w/a - 1
    - O'Brien, Fitzjames, poem, The Opal Seeker, ND., ADS - 2
    - O'Brien, Fitzjames, poem, Rose de Mai, ND., AD - 1 w/a by L.C.
    - O'Brien, Fitzjames, poem, Rose de Mai, ND., PD, no source - 1
    - O'Brien, Fitzjames, caricature of, by Edward Mullen, 1861., Printed tearsheet from Vanity Fair, w/a on verso
    - Article by Francis Wolle, Fitz-james O'Brien's Irish Background from AIHS's The Recorder [1939]., Tearsheets - 3
    - [Re Fitzjames O'Brien] Gen. McClellan to Wm. Winter, 11-1-80, ALS w/a - 2
    - [Re Fitzjames O'Brien] 2 auction notices, 1939
    - Review of biography of O'Brien by F. Woole, 1944 -, 1
    - O'Brien, Frederick (Sausalito) to RC, 12-18-22., TLS - 1
    - O'Brien, Frederick (Sausalito) to RC, 12-17-28., TLS - 1
    - O'Brien, Frederick (Sausalito) to RC, 1-9-29., TLS w/a - 1
    - O'Brien, Frederick (Sausalito) to [RC], 6-20-29., TLS - 1
    - O'Brien, Frederick (Sausalito) to RC, 9-4-29., TLS - 1
    - O'Brien, Frederick (Sausalito) to [RC], 2-15-31., TLS - 1
    - O'Brien, Frederick (Scarborough) to [RC], Wednesday., TLS - 1
    - O'Brien, James J. (NYC) to JAH, 1-27-42., ALS - 1 [enc. 2 photographs of JBY's tombstone, now in PHOTOGRAPHS folder]
    - O'Brien, James J. (NYC) to JAH, 2-25-42., ALS - 1
  - O'CASEY, SEAN; O'CONNOR, J.F. (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - [O'Casey], Sean (L) to OG, 11-5-28., ALS - 1 w/cov. (1)
    - [O'Casey], Sean (L) to OG, 10-8-29., ALS - 1 (1)
    - O'Casey, Sean (L) to [AE], Editor, Irish Statesman, 1-7-30., Trans: TL - 2 w/cov. annotated by [IH]
    - O'Casey, Sean, review article, Charles Lever's Stormy Life, Sunday Times, 2-5-39
    - O'Connor, J. Frank (Palo Alto) to JAH, 4-7-61., TLS - 2
    - O'Connor, J. Frank, play, Deirdre in Dublin, ND., TmimeoD - (ii) + 50. Autograph inscription to JAH on titlepage
    - O'Connor, J. Frank, article, You can buy..., Sunday Independent, 3-25-62
  - O'CONNOR, ULICK (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - O'Connor, U. (D) to OG, ND., ALS - 6
    - O'Connor, U. (D) to JAH, 12-6-58., ALS - 7 w/cov.
    - O'Connor, U. (D) to JAH, 1-24-59., ALS - 1 w/cov.
    - O'Connor, U. (Greystones) to JAH, 2-7-60., ALS - 6 w/cov.
    - O'Connor, U. (La Gaude, France) TO JAH, [9-19-61]., ALS - 2 w/cov [sent from Ireland]
    - O'Connor, U. (D) to Editor, Irish Independent, 2-7-65., Clipping - 1
    - Ca. 6 clippings re U. O'Connor
    - Article re Gogarty in 6 parts, in Sunday Independent 7-5-64 to 8-23-64, (1)
    - Ca. 12 newspaper reviews of O'Connor's biography of Gogarty, 1964.Reviewers include Austin Clarke, PC, Richard Ellmann, and Sean O'Faolain
  - O'DONOVAN, M.; O'DWYER, D.; O'FAOLAIN, S. (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - O'Donovan, Michael (NP) to ECY, ND., ALS - 1
    - O'Dwyer, David T. (Glenwood Springs, Colo.) to RC, 4-28-35., ALS - 4 and trans: TL - 2 (2)
    - O'Dwyer, David T. (Washington, D. C.) to JAH, 4-6-37., ALS - 2
    - O'Faolain, Sean (D) to EAB, 12-18-38., TNS - 1
  - O'FLAHERTY, LIAM (Box 10, Folder 160)
    - Autograph manuscript introduction to The Back-to-Backs, ND., ADS - 3
    - 2 clippings re, 1940, (3)
    - 3 sale notices re AMSs and books
  - O'GRADY, STANDISH (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 3-24-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 2
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 4-11-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 1
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, [received 5-11-93]., Pc of ALS - 3
    - O'Grady, Standish (NP) to Mr. Colles, [received 5-13-1893]., Pc of ALS - 1
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 6-5-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 1
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 6-15-[1893]., ALS - 1 (2)
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 7-11-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 2
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 12-8-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 4
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 12-20-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 2
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 12-22-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 2
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 1-10-[1894]., Pc of ALS - 3
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Colles, 4-11-[?]., ALS - 2
    - O'Grady, Standish (Wicklow) to Dear Manager., ALS - 1 (2)
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Mr. Moores, 1-11-[1894]., ALS - 2 (2)
    - O'Grady, Standish (Anglesea Road,?) to AE, 9-5-?., Pc of ALS - 4
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Dear Sir, 1-13-1893., Pc of ALS - 3
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Dear Sir, 2-6-[1893]., ALS - 1
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Dear Sir, 3-9-[1893]., ALS - 3
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Dear Sir, 8-15-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 3
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Dear Sir, 9-20-[1893]., Pc of ALS - 2
    - O'Grady, Standish (D) to Dear Sir, 4-2-[1895]., ALS - 2 (1)
    - Auction note re 2 O'Grady ALSs